Guide to the Mary Bridges-Adams Collection on British Labour Movement and Russian Socialists,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Georgii Checherin Materials, 1908-1918, undated
  - Subseries II.1: Correspondence, 1912-1917, undated
    - Correspondence with organizations, 1915-1917 undated:
      - Section Relations Internationals Sovnep: see Subject correspondence (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Southampton Council for Civil Liberties, Southampton, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Sotsialisticheskii klub-stolovaia, London, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - South West Ham Socialist Sunday School, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Trades and Labour Council, 1915-1917(arranged in alphabetical order by the branch name) (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Twentieth Century Press, Ltd., London, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Union Democratic Control, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - War Office, Whitehall, 1916-1917 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Winberg, formerly Gibraltar Press, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Workers' Suffrage Federation, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Workers' Union, Ebbw Vale, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Young Socialist: A Magazine of Justice and Love, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Outgoing letters (drafts of letters to various people mostly addressed as "comrade"), 1915-1917 (see also Subject and unidentified correspondence) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Subject correspondence: Correspondence regarding the movie sale, 1917
      - Chicherin to Rozanov (two letters) (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Chicherin to K.D. Nabokov (note on a back of Chicherin's business card) (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Dolivo-Dobrovol'skii, G. to K.D. Nabokov (Box 2, Folder 14)
        (telegram)
      - Section Relations Internationals Sovnep to Chicherin (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Subseries II.2: Writings and Research Materials, 1914-1916, undated
    Comprises drafts and copies of speeches and articles, notes, and extracts from articles by others.
    - Drafts of articles and speeches, undated, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
      (8 holograph manuscripts. See also Subseries II.4: Activity in Various Organizations--Russian Political Prisoners and Exiles Relief Committee in London. Box 3, Folders 7-16 and Flat Box #4, Folders 5-6)
    - Extracts from various letters and articles by others, 1914-1916 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
    - Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Subseries II.3: Documents and Contacts, 1908-1917, undated
    This subseries includes documents related to Chicherin's detention and deportation; his business cards; receipts and notes, address book and business cards of various people.
    - Detention and Deportation, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Receipts and notices, France, England, 1908-1917 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Chicherin's business cards, London, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Contacts:
      - Address book, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
        (with enclosures)
      - Business cards and notes with a contact information of various people, undated (Box 2, Folder 24-36)
        (arranged alphabetically)
  - Subseries II.4: Activity in various organizations, 1914-1917
    Contains appeals, circulars, resolutions, financial reports, flyers, leaflets, brochures, minutes of meetings, accounts for various activities, and printed materials from British press related to Chicherin's involvement with various organizations' activity, including Russian socialist groups and Russian Political Prisoners and Exiles Relief Committee in London. Organizations are listed in alphabetical order.
    - Committee of Delegates of the Russian Socialist Groups in London, 1916-1917, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - International Socialist Conference, Zimmerwald, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Komitet pomoshchi politkatorzhanam i ssyl'noposelentsam: see Russian Political Prisoners and Exiles Relief Committee
    - Londonskaia gruppa RSDRP, 1915, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Russian Delegates Committee, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Russian Political Prisoners and Exiles Relief Committees in France, 1914-1916 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Russian Political Prisoners and Exiles Relief Committee in Krakow, 1914-1917 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Russian Political Prisoners and Exiles Relief Committee in London (oversize materials are stored in Flat Box #4): (Box 3, Folder 7-16)
      - Bylaws, 1915 (see also oversize materials stored in Flat Box #4, Folder 4) (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Addresses, appeals, 1915, undated (drafts, flyers, reprints. See also oversize materials stored in Flat Box #4, Folder 4) (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Agendas, minutes, reports, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
      - Financial reports and statements, receipts, 1915-1916 (handwritten and printed) (Box 3, Folder 11-14)
      - Printed materials:
        - Listok Organizatsii pomoshchi politicheskim zakliuchennym, 1916 No.3 (two copies) (Box 3, Folder 15)
        - Fliers, adds, 1916, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
        - Clippings including Bridges-Adams's and Chicherin's publications in British press, 1915-1916 (Box 3, Folder 16)
          (Cotton Factory Times, Justice, The Leichester Pioneer, The Railway Review, Socialist, The Western Daily Press, Yorkshire Factory Times. See also oversize materials stored in Flat Box #4, Folders 5-6)
  - Subseries II.5: Printed Materials, 1915-1918, undated
    There are addresses, appeals, manifestos, articles by others printed as manuscripts, and two Russian newspapers. More printed materials are part of other series and subseries.
    - Addresses, appeals, manifestos:
      - Kerenskii, M.. "Inter-Allied Labour and Socialist Conference", 1918 (Box 4, Folder 7)
        (galley proofs, oversize, stored in Flat Box #4, Folder 7)
      - "Manifesto to All Trade Unionists of the Rank and File Council against Conscription of the Licensed Vehicle Workers", undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
        (oversize, stored in Flat Box #4, Folder 7)
      - Russian Anti-Conscription League, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Articles-- Printed as Manuscripts, undated
      - L.V. "Na vernom puti" (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Merkgeim. Article for Nashe Slovo (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Unidentified (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Newspapers and Magazines:
      - Nashe Slovo: obshchestvennaia i politicheskaia gazeta, Paris, September-October, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 8)
        (three issues; oversize, stored in Flat Box #4, Folder 8)
      - Sotsialdemokrat: Tsentral'nyi organ Rossiiskoi Sotsialdemokraticheskoi partii, Geneva, December 1915 No.49 (Box 4, Folder 8)
        (oversize, stored in Flat Box #4, Folder 8)
      - Young Socialist: A Magazine of Justice and Love, Glasgow, 1917 vol. XVII, No.5: see Series: Chicherin Papers--Subseries: Correspondence--Correspondence with Organizations-- Young Socialist (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Ephemera--lottery and concert tickets, fliers, resolution, 1917, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)